Alejandro García

Core Skill:

Project Management

Industry Verticals:

Banking Telcos Media Healthcare Technology

Tools & Techniques:

Agile PMI Jira Scrum

Summary:

Telecommunications Engineer, Project Management Professional, and ITIL v4 foundations certified. with extensive experience in management, analysis, and operation of IT Services for different industries such as telecommunications, banking, media, and health care, working in multicultural environments providing value to customers and end users. Skilled in Customer Service, Customer Relationship Management (CRM), strategic project management, and Business Process Improvement.

Qualifications:

Educational Background:

Telecommunications Engineer, Universidad Distriltal, 2013

Certifications:

ITIL V4 Foundation, AXELOS Global Best Practices, 2020 Project Management Professional (PMP), PMI, 2018

Spoken Languages:

Spanish, Native English, B2+

Soft Skills:

Analysis
Autonomy
Client oriented
Management
Problem Solving
Risk
Strong Analytical Skills
Organization

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Industry sector: Healthcare				
Agile Project Manager				
2023-05-01 - Currently				
Project descriptions:	Responsibilities:			
* Discovery into the Client's Application technology estate (code base, data, infrastructure), and preferred business, technology support, and software development processes; * Redesign of the AWS cloud service infrastructure to improve security, reliability and cost-effectiveness; * Redesign of back-end architecture to improve code quality and reduce code base complexity * Software engineering of production-ready front-end and back-end code to continue to evolve and improve against existing Client product functionality and features.	Responsible for the day-to-da project within the constraints shoard and sponsor and ensur produces the required product scope, risk, and benefit performance of the product	set out by the project ing that the project ts by the time, cost,		
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:		
	Agile, Scrum, Confluence, Jira, GitHub, AWS services			

Industry sector: Media					
Service Delivery Manager					
2020-06-01 - 2022-12-30	0				
Project descriptions:	Responsibilities:				
* Provide a set of manage services such as Service Desk, Infrastructure support and EUC support * Ensure the correct operation and high availability of the client's infrastructure * Provide support to McC employees through the 24/7 help desk	Managing day to day delivery of services in order to achieve the agreed Service Level Targets. Acting as a bridge between client-dedicated account teams and Managed Services and other shared delivery teams. Owning the transition of projects and services into live service. Acting as a single point of contact for client counterparts for end-to-end delivery of projects and services throughout the lifecycle. Managing Continuous Service Improvement Program. Reporting activity through a range of regular and adhoc reports.				
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:			
	AWS services, Linux, Microsoft Azure, SQL				